<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sebastian Lobentanzer</title>
    <link>https://slobentanzer.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sebastian Lobentanzer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://slobentanzer.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://slobentanzer.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slobentanzer.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>About I am a pharmacologist turned research software engineer, and I am particularly interested in disentangling causal relationships in molecular biology. I pursue this goal as a part of the lab of Julio Saez-Rodriguez at the Heidelberg University Hospital since 2021, and in affiliation with the Open Targets group at the European Bioinformatics Institute (EMBL-EBI) since 2024.
Effectively dealing with the avalanche of biomedical measurements of today - without throwing away large parts of the data - requires a smart digital infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://slobentanzer.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slobentanzer.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications In the following, you can find a list of highlighted publications with short summaries. For all publications, please see my Google Scholar profile.
perspective: Lobentanzer S#, Rodriguez-Mier P, Bauer S, Saez-Rodriguez J# (2024) Molecular causality in the advent of foundation models Molecular Systems Biology. doi: https://doi.org/10.1038/s44320-024-00041-w. (#: corresponding authors)
Exploration of and perspective on the tradeoff between simplicity and complexity in molecular modelling, with a focus on current trends in deep learning and their potential application in causal inference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://slobentanzer.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slobentanzer.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Teaching I have been teaching a variety of courses since the beginning of my PhD in 2015, usually single-topic courses and short series between 2 and 8 hours, in several areas of the life sciences and computer science.
Computer Science Machine and deep learning track, Ukrainian Biological Data Science Summer School 2024 (Uzhhorod, Ukraine).
Summer school on &amp;lsquo;LLM deployment in the cloud&amp;rsquo;, German Center of Competence in Cloud Computing for Data Management and Data Processing, 2024.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
