<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sebastian lobentanzer</title>
    <link>https://slobentanzer.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on sebastian lobentanzer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><atom:link href="https://slobentanzer.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://slobentanzer.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slobentanzer.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>About I am a pharmacologist turned research software engineer, and I am particularly interested in disentangling causal relationships in molecular biology. I pursue this goal as a part of the lab of Julio Saez-Rodriguez at the Heidelberg University Hospital.
Effectively dealing with the avalanche of biomedical measurements of today - without throwing away large parts of the data - requires a smart digital infrastructure. Thus, I am actively developing a unified framework for biomedical knowledge representation, BioCypher, as well as the prior knowledge database OmniPath and its infrastructural backend, pypath, with the aim of automating harmonisation of biomedical representations for a multitude of research tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://slobentanzer.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slobentanzer.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications In the following, you can find a list of highlighted publications with short summaries. For all publications, please see my Google Scholar profile.
preprint: Lobentanzer S, Saez-Rodriguez J (2023) A platform for the biomedical application of Large Language Models arXiv, doi: https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06488
BioChatter is an extension of the BioCypher ecosystem that enables the modular integration of Large Language Models into biomedical workflows. Its prototype frontend, ChatGSE demonstrates some capabilities of the framework in facilitating human-machine collaboration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://slobentanzer.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slobentanzer.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Teaching I have been teaching a variety of courses since the beginning of my PhD in 2015, usually single-topic courses and short series between 2 and 8 hours, in several areas of the life sciences.
Meta-science (seminar series) GRADE Postgraduate Seminar Series &amp;lsquo;Reproducibility in Biomedical Research&amp;rsquo; (Goethe University Frankfurt). MSc module &amp;lsquo;Reproducibility in Biomedical Research&amp;rsquo; (University Clinic Heidelberg, Molecular Bioscience and Molecular Biotechnology programs) Pharmacology (single or double courses of 3-6 hours) Basics of pharmacology: pharmacodynamics, pharmacokinetics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
