<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sebastian Lobentanzer</title>
    <link>https://slobentanzer.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sebastian Lobentanzer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://slobentanzer.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://slobentanzer.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slobentanzer.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>About Lab Website: https://slolab.ai
I am a pharmacologist turned research software engineer, and I am particularly interested in disentangling causal relationships in molecular biology with the help of modern artificial intelligence approaches. I pursue this goal as a Principal Investigator at the Institute of Computational Biology at Helmholtz Center Munich since 2025, and in affiliation with the Open Targets group at the European Bioinformatics Institute (EMBL-EBI) since 2024. I also serve as the head of computational biology at the German Center for Diabetes Research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://slobentanzer.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slobentanzer.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications In the following, you can find a list of highlighted publications with short summaries. For all publications, please see my Google Scholar profile.
paper: Kuehl M, Schaub DP, Carli F, Heumos L, Hellmig M, Fernández-Zapata C, Kaiser N, Schaul J, Kulaga A, Usanov N, Scverse Community, Krebs CF, Panzer U, Bonn S, Lobentanzer S§, Saez-Rodriguez J§, Puelles VG§ (2025) BioContextAI is a community hub for agentic biomedical systems Nature Biotechnology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://slobentanzer.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slobentanzer.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Teaching I have been teaching a variety of courses since the beginning of my PhD in 2015, usually single-topic courses and short series between 2 and 8 hours, in several areas of the life sciences and computer science.
Computer Science Data integration and LLMs in the Machine Learning and AI Summer School (VIB, Belgium, 2025)
EMBL-EBI webinar on LLM technologies and future directions (2025, recording available)
Machine and deep learning track, Ukrainian Biological Data Science Summer School 2024 (Uzhhorod, Ukraine).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
