<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sebastian lobentanzer</title>
    <link>https://slobentanzer.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on sebastian lobentanzer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://slobentanzer.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://slobentanzer.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slobentanzer.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>About I am a pharmacologist turned bioinformatician, particularly interested in disentangling causal relationships in molecular biology. I pursue this goal as a part of the lab of Julio Saez-Rodriguez at the University Clinic of Heidelberg. Effectively dealing with the avalanche of biomedical measurements of today - without &amp;ldquo;throwing away&amp;rdquo; large parts of the data - requires a smart digital infrastructure. Thus, I am actively developing a unified language for biomedical property graph databases, BioCypher, as well as the prior knowledge database OmniPath and its infrastructural backend, pypath, with the aim of automating harmonisation of biomedical representations for a multitude of research tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://slobentanzer.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slobentanzer.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications Monograph Lobentanzer S (2020) Small RNA Dynamics in Cholinergic Systems. Dissertation, defended 2nd of October 2020 (summa cum laude), available at http://publikationen.ub.uni-frankfurt.de/frontdoor/index/index/docId/56125
Peer-reviewed manuscripts Lobentanzer S, Klein J, Soreq H (2020) Establishing human male and female models of cholinergic neurons via neurokine-mediated differentiation of LA-N-2 and LA-N-5 neuroblastoma cells. STAR Protocols, 1 (3), doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xpro.2020.100193
Winek K†, Lobentanzer S†, Nadorp B, Dubnov S, Dames C, Jagdmann S, Moshitzky G, Hotter B, Meisel C, Greenberg DS, Shifman S, Klein J, Shenhar-Tsarfaty S, Meisel A, Soreq H (2020) Transfer RNA fragments replace microRNA regulators of the cholinergic post-stroke immune blockade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://slobentanzer.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slobentanzer.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Teaching I have been teaching a variety of courses since the beginning of my PhD in 2015, usually single-topic courses and short series between 2 and 8 hours, in several areas of the life sciences.
Meta-science (seminar series)  GRADE Postgraduate Seminar Series &amp;lsquo;Reproducibility in Biomedical Research&amp;rsquo; (Goethe University Frankfurt). MSc module &amp;lsquo;Reproducibility in Biomedical Research&amp;rsquo; (University Clinic Heidelberg, Molecular Bioscience and Molecular Biotechnology programs)  Pharmacology (single or double courses of 3-6 hours)  Basics of pharmacology:  pharmacodynamics, pharmacokinetics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
